SUMMARY

A full stack developer with 1+ years of experience, and with a passion for developing applications in Ruby, React, and Javascript, built over 20+ projects using different tech stacks with user accessibility and pixel-perfect design. Collaborated with 50+ developers across the world remotely and I had the chance to work with teams and delivered projects successfully. I am a passionate software developer and believe in creating something new out of the box.

EXPERIENCE

Microverse, Remote Remote
Mentor May 2022 - Present

- Mentored 15+ junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews with 1:1 interaction. As the experience is ongoing, the verbs should be in the present tense to reflect the current situation.
- Propose improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance by 50%.
- Provide advice and tips on maintaining motivation to maintain longevity in the program.

Fever, Remote Remote Freelancer August 2021 – Present

 Create optimized, scalable, secure, and responsive 10+ websites.

- Create engaging and high-quality written content for clients.
- Receive 5-star ratings with positive feedback on all projects or works.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE May 2022 – Present Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

TRIBHUWN UNIVERSITY June 2007-July 2010

 Bachelor in Science, Major in Physics, Minor in Mathematics Received the Appreciation Medal. I got 3rd position in my stream batch

<u>GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | Portfolio</u> libraryismyparadise@gmail.com

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, MySQL, Postgresql, Python, NodeJs

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Render, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, Jest, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools, Agile Development **Professional:** Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring, Multicultural Work experience.

PROJECTS

Space Travellers' Hub—A web application for a company that provides commercial and scientific space travel services. The application will allow users to book rockets and join selected space missions

 Built with: (Javascript, Es6, CSS3, HTML5, React, Redux, Jest)

Expense Tracker — A Ruby on Rails mobile web app that helps users manage their budget with transaction lists categorized for easy expense tracking.

 Built with (Ruby, Ruby on Rails, BootStrap, Rspec, and PostgreSQL)

<u>Coin Tracker</u> — Coin Tracker provides real-time market-based information and statistics about the top 52 cryptocurrencies in the market.

 Built with: (React, Redux, JavaScript, RestAPI CSS3, and Jest,)

<u>Coder's Hub</u> — Coders-Hub application allows users to reverse different online classes depending on their preferences. They are assigned a mentor for each course and also get to choose how long they want to participate in the course.

 Built with: (React, Redux, JavaScript,RestAPI Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Jest, Rspec andDoorKeeper)

Recipe App — The recipe App is an application that allows you to keep track of recipes, inventory, and ingredients, generate shopping lists for ingredients you lack for a recipe, and share your recipes (depending on their public or private status).

 Built with: (Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Rspec, BootStrap, CSS3)